What I have for you today is a polished
up version of a super value packed live
workshop that I just did yesterday. I
hosted the AI transformation workshop
with Lior Weinstein. He's a big name in
the AI space. It was a blast. And so
what you're about to see is my portion
of the event, teaching you in very
simple terms how to build a foundational
system for getting reliable and
repeatable results with AI coding
assistants. And this is important right
now because people they over engineer
and over complicated AI coding
frameworks all of the time, making it
seem like you need some fancy harness or
specialized agents just to do any real
work at scale. But that really isn't the
case. So I boil things down into the
core principles for AI coding here in
three phases, teaching you how to ideate
with coding agents, how to build an
iterative loop, and then how to evolve
your coding agents over time. A lot of
this I've covered on my channel, but
never in one place. There's a reason
this workshop is one hour. It's super
value packed. You If you go through this
entire thing, you come out of it with a
full system that you have a real
ownership of. And the best part is it's
not even that complicated. And so
without further ado, here is the live
workshop. Our job as an engineer
is to no longer write the code, but to
do the higher leverage tasks like the
planning and validating. And that's the
framework that I want to cover here.
And um also for product managers in the
room, there's a lot that I have to say
that applies to you guys as well.
There's a three-part
process that I want to walk through with
you right now. We're going to start with
how do we ideate around the work that we
want our coding agents to do for us for
building literally anything, a website,
uh funnel, uh any kind of platform. This
is going to apply no matter what you
want to build. And then we'll get into
for the developer when we are knocking
out a piece of work like a ticket in
Jira or handling a GitHub issue or
starting a new application, what does
that process look like? It's using the
PIV loop. That's my core methodology
that we'll cover. And then we'll get
into the system evolution mindset. And
this is probably the most powerful part
of the entire system, how we make our
coding agents more powerful over time as
we run into issues using them.
And uh one disclaimer that I want to
give before we get into everything here
is that uh a lot of what I'm covering
here is a training that I do for
organizations. But usually for them it's
more of a 4-hour session where I really
get into the entire process. And so I've
compacted everything down into 1 hour to
share with you guys right now. So a
high-level overview, but I'm still going
to get really practical with you guys.
And I'm going to give you a live
demonstration of everything here so that
you can come out of this 1 hour knowing
exactly what the process looks like that
you can mold for yourself to go from
idea all the way to production code with
the help of a AI coding assistant. And
the important thing here is we're not
vibe coding because we are putting
ourselves in the driver seat along the
way through all of the planning and
validation that we do. That is the the
core framework that I'm going to cover
with you.
And uh really this whole process, it
applies no matter the tools that you're
using. And so I'm going to be using
Claude Code for our event here just
because that is my favorite AI coding
assistant, at least right now. And then
I'm going to be using Jira as my place
to manage all of the work that we scope
out with the help of Claude Code.
But this entire process is going to work
if you're using, you know, Codex with
GitHub or you're using GitHub Copilot
with Linear. Really it's just you need
to have one place to manage your work
and organize your work and then one
place to work with a large language
model to create your code. That's the
only requirement that I have here. Even
if you do want to follow along. And also
in the description for our live stream
here, if you click into the description,
I'm just like looking at it on my left
monitor here, I have a link to a GitHub
repository. And uh this GitHub
repository has the demonstration
application that we're going to be
building on top of today. And then it
also has all of the resources that I'm
going to be showcasing here, my rules,
my commands, my skills. We'll talk about
what those look like and I'll use some
of them live, but a lot of that it lives
here in the dot cloud folder. So, if you
see any part of my process that you
really want to steal for yourself,
please feel free to do so. This
repository is open source, ready for you
to come in and take any of the skills or
all the commands that I'm using to
package up my workflows. And so,
really we're not going to be doing a lot
of manually typing today because it's
going to be here are the prompts that
I've been using time and time again. I
have it as a command that I can
reference and have the coding agent go
through that procedure that I'm using
pretty much every single time that I'm
delegating in the coding to AI. So,
yeah, the last thing I want to say
before we get into things here is there
are a lot of frameworks for AI coding
available to us that are open source.
So, maybe you guys have explored GitHub
Spec Kit or B Mad or Claude Flow or GSD,
um Gas Town. I mean, I could go on
naming a dozens and dozens of them.
There are all of these opinionated
strategies out there right now to guide
you through a process kind of similar to
what I'm going to show you here. Like
this is a process for researching, then
planning, then building, then validating
with AI coding assistance driving a lot
of it.
And I have a lot of respect for these
platforms. There are a lot of really
powerful, timeless software engineering
strategies built into them, but at the
same time a lot of these frameworks are
very over-engineered. They try to do too
much at once and it's really difficult
to take an existing off-the-shelf
framework and mold it to your software
development life cycle.
So, like I said, I do a lot of corporate
trainings where I teach companies how to
take something very foundational like
this and mold it to their existing
practice because you don't want to just
throw out the window the entire process
your team has already been using for
working with coding agents. Instead, you
want to mold the process around AI, but
you still are going to have some of your
conventions in the way that the team
works. It's not really realistic to just
throw everything out the window. But,
when you're using something like BDD or
Gherkin, you're trying to take an
off-the-shelf solution, you're kind of
forced to do that because it's so
bloated that it's hard to like really
make it your own. And so, what I teach
here is simple on purpose cuz I want to
show you the foundation that you can
then build on top of to mold it into
your process for planning, your process
for QA, whatever that looks like for
each stage of the software development
life cycle.
And so, we'll start with planning here.
And planning, this part actually applies
to product managers just as much as
developers. So, a lot of organizations
that I work with, um the trainings that
I do, they'll bring their entire uh PM
team into the training as well because
they're actually the first ones that
have a touch point with the coding agent
when you're planning the next scope of
work for an application. So, the product
manager is the one initially doing, you
know, let's say the sprint planning. And
it's important for them, just like the
developers, to work with coding agents
to speed up that process. Here's the
application that we have right now. Here
are the bugs we want to fix and the
issues that we want to build or the new
features we want to build for this
sprint. And same thing applies to
greenfield development, you're going to
be building that initial scope of work
for the MVP of an application. And this
process applies to both.
And so, what I'm going to do with you
guys right now
is uh I am going to show this diagram at
a high level, just walk through it
really quickly with you, this component
right here, and then we're going to get
into something very practical. I'm going
to go into my uh code base here,
and we are going to go through
everything live. I'm going to show you
what it looks like for brownfield
development to take an existing
application, plan out a brand new sprint
with a bunch of new set sets of work we
want to perform,
and then I'm going to pick one of those,
and we're going to go through the piv
loop, the process that we're going to
repeat for every single Jira ticket. And
again, that could be a GitHub issue, it
could be a linear ticket, whatever that
is. And so, you'll see the full process
end to end. There's a lot of value that
I have packed into the hour for you guys
here. So, okay.
The beginning of the process here is as
simple as it possibly can be. You are
going to open up your coding agent, like
I'll, you know, I'll just pop open
Claude Code right here, and you're just
going to have a conversation about what
you want to build. There is no structure
at first. And like I said earlier, it is
simple on purpose, because I want the
barrier to entry for you to be so
incredibly low that you begin just
brainstorming ideas with the coding
agent, and then we're going to evolve to
more structure over time. And that's the
process that I'm going to share with you
as I start to bring in some skills and
commands that I have in my AI layer, in
my AI coding system.
And so, um first of all, when you have
this conversation, you just do what I
like to call a brain dump. Like most of
the time, I'll literally I'll just use a
speech-to-text tool, so that I just
talk. I go on and on about what I want
to build. At this point, it is helpful
to be as specific as possible. And so,
you would say, you know, like, "This is
my application. Here are the new things
that I want to build. Here are the bugs
I want to fix." And then you go into the
clarifying stage. And so, the most
important part when you're first
planning work with a coding agent is to
reduce the number of assumptions that it
is making, because honestly, most of the
time when a coding agent does a bad job,
it's not like the code is just broken.
It's that it's not aligned with what you
were actually looking to build. And
really, the responsibility is on you
there because it is your role to and and
your responsibility to make sure the
coding agent is really on the same page
with you for what you are building. So,
it's a lot of just curating this context
with the help of a coding agent, being
very specific for what you want to
build.
And so, the most powerful strategy here,
and you'll see this in action in just a
little bit, is to have the coding agent
ask you questions. Like we will
specifically ask it to ask us questions.
And you can go through this process for
a good 20, 30 minutes, even beyond that,
if you really want to set the stage well
going into the development later on. So,
product managers, this is your job when
you're working with Claude Code. And
even if you're you know, you're a solo
developer shipping things without a
product manager, this is still an
important step to go through. It's very
important to stay high-level at first.
We're not getting into the weeds right
now for how we're going to test things
or what files we have to change in our
code base. At this point, we're just
trying to figure out what are the
requirements that we need to translate
into code. And then we'll have a
separate planning process where we're
getting more into, okay, here's how
we're actually going to code it and the
parts of code of the code base that we
need to edit. So, at this point, we're
very, very high-level.
And then after you have a conversation
with the coding agent where you figured
out exactly what you want to build, what
is our scope of work for this sprint or
this new application, then it's time to
create your AI layer. And I have this
marked as optional here just because
when you are working on an existing code
base, you might already have that AI
layer already created. But if you don't
have it, I highly recommend investing a
lot of time up front building this. Now,
for our 1 hour here, it's not like I
have a lot of time to like really get
into best practices for building your
global rules and your skills and
commands. But I'm just saying like this
is the part of the workflow where you
will create that. And so, your global
rules, these are the conventions, the
rules that you always want your coding
agent to follow. Like here are our
coding styles, here's our testing
strategy, our logging strategy, things
like that. And then your commands, we're
going to see a lot of these in action
today. And your skills, these are your
reusable workflows. So, anytime you find
yourself prompting something more than
three times, you should turn it into a
command or skill. Because that's just a
prompt that you're going to load into
your coding agent when the time comes.
Like this is my process for planning,
this is my process for creating PRDs or
stories in Jira, for example.
That way we don't have to type things
out. And it's a reusable workflow that
we can share and create a standard
across with our team. Very, very
important. So, we don't want to do
manual prompting as much as possible,
turn things into something in the AI
layer that you can invoke, right? Like
we can take a command and skill and say,
you know,  plan. Now we are going
into our planning process.
And so, that actually goes into the
first command that we'll use here. And
again, I'll show this all in action in
just a little bit.
So, the first command is a process
guiding the coding agent from an
unstructured conversation into a
structured PRD. Like I said, we go from
exploration to structure. So that we
have a single document that is produced
from this command that outlines all of
the core sections for our and a PRD is
short for product requirement document.
So, this is like the initial scope of
work for an application if we're doing
greenfield development, or these are all
of the tickets that we need to handle if
it's a new sprint that we are planning
for in Jira, for example. And then I can
take the PRD and also have Claude code
split it up into individual pieces of
work to create as my Jira tickets. We'll
see this in action.
And so, it handles literally everything.
It parses this document. It figures out
what are the individual phases or pieces
of work that we should create as
tickets. And then we'll even use the
Jira MCP server to create those things
so that we don't have to do that
backstage work like Leora was talking
about of creating those tickets in Jira.
We want to have our coding agent handle
all of that administrative work.
And so, we end with tickets in Jira and
then we can pick one of them. So, this
is where, you know, the product manager
would hand things over to the developer
to pick a ticket and then go into the
full Piv loop. This is the full process
we go through to handle individual sets
of work with our coding agent. So, we'll
get into this next, but first I want to
show you a live demonstration of our
ideation phase.
And so, I'll go over to my code base
now.
And I'll it's just describe very briefly
the application that I have for a
demonstration here.
And so, this repository, again, I have
it linked in the description. I also
linked it in the chat.
Um actually, I didn't link it in the
chat, so I'll do that right now. So, let
me go out, copy this.
And I'll paste this in our chat here. If
you guys want to just poke around the
resources that I have for you guys and
or even follow along, you can feel free
to do that. Uh the application for my
demonstration is just the quick poll
builder. So, you know, you put in your
question like uh how experienced are you
with AI coding? And then we have our
options here like I'm a beginner, I'm
intermediate, or I am advanced. All
right, cool. And then I create a poll.
Yeah, the point of this application is
that it's super simple because I'm going
to be focusing on the process, not
focusing on the application itself,
right? So, I want something very quick
to build on top of so that I can quickly
go through how I create stories, handle
tickets, go through the pivot loop, and
the system evolution.
And so, uh what I'm going to do to begin
is I'm going to go into Cloud Code, and
I'm going to plan my next fictitious
sprint. So, we have this very basic
application right now where we can
create a poll, and if I, you know,
actually had the application deployed,
then people could use it and go and and
answer the poll, but there are a lot of
features that are missing. And so, I
have a prompt prepared ahead of time
that I'm just going to paste in right
now, just so that you guys don't have to
watch paint dry as I give my initial
brain dump. But again, this is your
point where you just dump all of your
ideas of what you want to build, being
as specific as possible. So, even if you
wanted to specify things like your tech
stack and your architecture, if you're
more technical, this is where you do
that. But even if you are less
technical, and you are, you know,
product manager, for example, you can
still stay pretty high-level here, and
just describe the features that you want
to build.
And so, I'm saying like here's my brain
dump for phase two, like the next thing
that I want to build on top of the
application. Let's say I want to build a
live presentation mode. Like right now
in the poll builder, when I I can't
really like see answers come in live.
Like if I click see current results, I'd
have to refresh the page in order to see
new entries.
I also want to build a QR code
generation, multi-question polls,
multiple choice questions. Like there's
like a lot of things that I want to
build on top. This is my next sprint
that I want to uh you know, my end goal
is to have all these things created as
uh Jira tickets that I could then pass
on to developers, or pass on to my
coding agents if I am a developer.
And so, I've described everything here.
Um usually, if I'm not just doing a live
demonstration, I would make this prompt
a lot longer, but I just wanted to keep
it concise right now. And then the
important thing here, this is what I was
saying in the diagram, before you write
anything, ask me clarifying questions
one at a time using the ask user
question tool.
And so now this is where I'm going to
make sure that I get on the same page
with my coding agent.
And so one at a time it's going to ask
me these questions and in Claude code we
have this ask user question tool where
we can see these questions pop up with a
multiple choice answers for us. So it's
really easy to blitz through things cuz
a lot of times what it recommends is
actually what I'm going to go with, but
it still gives me the opportunity if I
want to say like, "Hey, no, you're wrong
here. Like let's actually do it this way
instead." So we can, you know, remove
that that incorrect assumption that it
was making.
And for other coding agents that don't
have this specific tool, it's this whole
process is still going to work. It's
just going to be a little bit slower cuz
you'll have to type out each of your
answers more like you're just chatting
with an agent. Um but it still works in
exactly the same way. So it's asking us
questions here like how should real-time
updates work? I'll just go with what it
recommends here just for the sake of
speed, but also you have this option to
chat with it. So for each individual
thing if you really want to dive deep
with the coding agent, which a lot of
times I would recommend you do, you have
the opportunity to do that.
And of course how deep you go does
depend on how technical you really are.
Like right there, you know, how should
real-time updates work? That is a pretty
technical question. So if you want to
just go with what it recommends, that's
definitely okay. But if you have that
knowledge and then like really
understand the architecture of the code
base, it's just more power to you.
You're able to to really make sure that
you clear assumptions. Otherwise if
you're, you know, more on the product
manager side, you might have a couple of
wrong assumptions that sneak into your
Jira tickets, but that's why you work
with the developers as you're planning
things, right? Like you'd have your
sprint meeting where you'd make sure you
clarify these kinds of things.
Uh but the goal is just for the coding
agent to help us with that starting
point of having all the context in Jira
ready for developers to refine and pick
up and work on.
And so, for the sake of demo, I'm going
to say let's end the questions here.
Just because sometimes it can go on for,
you know, a good 10-15 minutes asking us
a lot of questions. I'll allow it to
make some assumptions for the sake of
speed. But at this point, you know, I've
already shown you what I need for what
this process generally looks like. And
so, at the end of our chat here, this
context, this short-term memory for
Claude code, is what we're going to turn
into the PRD. So, we are about to run
our first command where we create that
product requirement document. The input
is the conversation. The output is a
single document, a source of truth that
we could, you know, then upload to
Confluence or check into source control,
wherever you want to store that, and
then we can create the Jira tickets from
that.
All right. So, that was the last
question there. Now, it's it's taking in
my message. So, it will move on to
creating our PRD. And Claude code is
smart enough to know the capabilities
are available. So, when I've gone
through this process a lot of times,
it'll just go right to loading the
create PRD skill, and it'll walk itself
through creating that document in
exactly the structure that I'm looking
for.
And so, I'll go ahead and open that so
we can see ahead of time what it
actually looks like. And again, all of
these commands that I'm about to walk
through are available in the GitHub
repository that I have linked in the
description. So, I'll go to create PRD.
That is our first command. And again,
commands and skills are really just
procedures. They are prompts that we get
to load in in real time whenever we
want. And so, create PRD. This is going
to generate a comprehensive product
requirements document. We are we get to
also specify like where it also outputs
this file. So, commands and skills
support arguments. So, that's how we can
make things dynamic. And we'll we'll
talk about arguments quite a bit cuz
most [snorts] of my procedures have
arguments. So, I can make them specific
to what I am doing right now.
And the main thing that we are outlining
in this PRD
command is the structure that we're
looking for. Like, we want every PRD to
have an executive summary, a mission,
target users. This is a lot of product
manager speak. So, if you come from the
product manager space, really this is
your opportunity to take how you already
write PRDs and make it so your coding
agent does it in the exact same thing.
Again, the foundations that I'm laying
for here in this process is not for you
to completely have a blank slate for
your software development life cycle,
but to take your best practices that you
established as a team and teach it to
your agents. That's what we're doing
with skills and commands. And so, your
PRDs are going to look the same, but
your agent is saving you hours and hours
and hours because it gets to generate
this based on our conversation.
And so, right here like what I can do is
it kind of
went through this itself like it loaded
the skill automatically, but I'll just
show you like if I wanted to invoke it
myself, I can just do create PRD. And
then I can specify the file name as an
argument like this. It's just when you
invoke something or similar to when you
invoke something in the command line for
all you developers. So, we just have
space separated arguments for anything
that we want the command to respect like
where we're going to output it. So,
we're going to have something in the dot
agents folder. It'll just be like a
marked out PRD in markdown file. And
then of course we could you know like
use the Jira MCP server to upload or the
Atlassian MCP server to upload it to
Confluence. We could upload this
document to Google Drive or put it as
context in a GitHub issue. However, you
want to you know store this artifact
that is like the initial source of truth
for that new application or that new
sprint that we are planning.
And so, once we have our PRD created and
it's going to take a little bit um,
because it's generating a larger
document here. You can see that Claude
is currently thinking through the
structure. So, it's taking this
conversation, reasoning about everything
that we we have discussed here, and then
creating a document from that. Once we
have our PRD, we are going to create our
stories. Now, you could do this as a
single command, where you create the PRD
and the stories all with a single call
to Claude Code. The reason I have these
separated is because once you have the
PRD created, it is a good time for you
to validate things yourself. So, going
back to the diagram here,
it is important for us to delegate as
much coding to the coding agent as we
possibly can. That's the backstage work
for developers now. But, we want to
remain in the driver's seat because
every single artifact that our coding
agent produces, whether it's a PRD or
it's a set of code, we want to review
that. And we want to have human in the
loop so that we can iterate on anything.
And so, when we create our PRD, it's not
good enough to just immediately create
stories from that. Like, it's important
for us to review the artifact and make
sure that things are really aligned with
what we are looking to do next. Because,
yes, we had it ask a bunch of clarifying
questions, but maybe we didn't have it
ask enough questions. Or maybe it didn't
quite understand our answers. That's why
it's important for us to still review
things. So, I I know that takes some
time, and the promise with AI is that it
speeds things up a lot. But, even if you
do take time refining the PRD with the
coding agent, it's still going to save
you so many hours compared to if you did
this entire process yourself.
And so, for the create stories command,
we run this after we have reviewed the
PRD and maybe made some changes to it.
And so, for this command, we give it the
path to our PRD. Obviously, we want
Claude code to know like this is the PRD
that we want to create our stories from.
And then we can also specify the Jira
project and epic. And so, what I have in
Jira created ahead of time is I just
have a a simple project created with an
epic that doesn't have any tasks in it
right now. So, this is what we're going
to populate live in a little bit with
our create stories command.
And so, I had to do a little bit of
manual work to actually create the epic.
But after that point, I'm not doing any
work myself in the Jira platform. That's
all backstage. I don't want to do that
myself. And so, I want to have a single
process
that goes from here are my ideas to
everything is populated here. And it
feels like magic every time this
happens. So, we'll get to that in a
second, but obviously, we need to have
the PRD created first. And you can see
that right now. It's outputting a lot of
tokens cuz it's in the middle of
creating that file for us. So, we just
have to be patient. But uh that gives me
some time here just to show you really
quickly what uh we have in this command
here.
So, first of all,
we have a phase-by-phase procedure that
we're walking Claude code through.
Again, commands are just prompts that
we're we're having the coding agent run
through.
So, we're having it load the PRD cuz we
can also run this in a separate Claude
code session if we don't want to run it
in the same one. So, we can load the
PRD. That's all the context it needs.
Then it's going to break down into
stories, and I can render this so it
looks a little bit nicer here. So, we
create a user story, and we can specify
the format as well. We can define the
acceptance criteria. So, just like we
create the structure for the PRD in the
create PRD command, we can do the same
thing for the stories here. So, your
team probably already has a convention.
Or if you're a solar solo developer, you
still probably have some kind of
convention for how you want to create
these artifacts. Here are my tasks, here
are my issues, whatever that is. And so
we bake that into the command.
And that makes it more reliable,
repeatable, and it makes it so that you
don't have to have a brand new process
that everyone is extremely uncomfortable
with, right? Like we want to make it
easy to adopt these new tools and new
processes.
And so then we go on to the structure
for each story. Here is exactly what
you're going to create. Here's how we're
going to order them. We even have some
validation built in, so it kind of
checks its own work to make sure that it
has, you know, fully extracted all the
phases out of the PRD, for example. And
then we have the output. We're going to
save everything to markdown documents.
And then if we have the Jira
integration, so I actually set this
command up so that if you're not working
with Jira, then you can still just work
with the stories in local files. A lot
of solo developers just manage their
entire system with markdown. And that's
totally respectable. So this command
works for that. But if we do have the
Jira integration,
and we tell it how to check for that,
then it's going to create everything in
the epic that we specified um in the
argument here. So like if these things
are filled in, and we'll see that in
just a second. So okay, we created our
PRD.
And so we can take a look at this.
So this document, I'm not going to read
through the entire thing right now, cuz
it's a pretty long document. The point
of uh what I'm demonstrating right here
is mainly to show you that the structure
that we have laid out in the create PRD
command is exactly what we see in our
final PRD. So we have our executive
summary, our mission, our target users,
everything that I showed you in the
markdown here.
And then we also have what is in scope.
So for our phase two sprint, we want the
multi-question polls, per user toggle,
the full-screen presenter presentation
page, uh everything that we gave in our
initial brain dump.
So this PRD is the result of our
conversation plus the create PRD
process, right? Like those two things
together, this is the baby of that.
And so now this PRD, we can run through
our create stories command.
And this is the thing is like after that
initial brain dump, I'm really not doing
much typing. I'm running commands, I'm
answering questions, that's really all I
have to do.
And so I'm going to go ahead and copy
this. And like I said, you could do this
in a separate context window if you
wanted to, but I'm just going to do it
right here because it was relatively
short. So I'm not going to iterate on
the PRD for the sake of speed here.
Um so I mean this is one moment where
it's, you know, do as I say not as I do,
but uh generally if I am off camera and
really working through my initial
planning for something, I'm going to
spend a lot of time looking through each
section here and making sure that
everything is as I intend. And so I'll
run create stories with uh the path to
my PRD, and then I have to give the ID
of my Jira project and also the ID of my
tag. And so for those of you who are
using Jira, you just get that like this
is the ID of your project and then this
is the ID of your epic.
And then if you're doing something else
like using GitHub or Linear, you're
going to go through the exact same
process. You're just going to use, you
know, the GitHub CLI to create issues
instead of the Jira MCP server or you're
going to use the Linear MCP server. So
again, it doesn't matter in the end what
tool you're actually using. So I'm going
to go ahead and run this.
So it's going to break down, it's going
to follow that exact process that I just
showed you, breaking down the PRD, and
then after a few minutes, it'll take a
little bit of time for it to reason
about that, we'll see all of the
subtasks start to get populated here in
Jira. And then at that point, we can
have developers just pick them up and go
through the pivot loop that I'll cover
with you guys next.
And that's the beauty of it is also you
can have developers work on everything
in parallel. They can assign themselves,
you can also, you know, use the Jira MCP
server to have the the developer get
assigned automatically when it picks up
a piece of work. You can create a system
in your task management software where
really agents are managing everything.
It's kind of like the the whole CTO X OS
that Lior was showing you guys where you
have the agent managing all of the grunt
work of organizing and um you know, all
of the you know, CRUD operations of
creating tasks and updating them and
assigning them and everything. We can
have agents manage all of that with the
Jira MCP server.
And I'll show you guys what that looks
like. If if you go into Cloud Code and
do  MCP, you can see that I have
the Atlassian
uh MCP server connected. So, by the way,
this also gives me access to Confluence,
not just Jira. So, if you wanted to like
store documents in Confluence, like you
wanted to store the PRD in Confluence
and then have a developer load that PRD
with the Jira MC or the Atlassian MCP
server, they can do that as well. Um and
so, if you are an Atlassian kind of shop
where you have Confluence and you have
Jira, you can have your coding agents
manage all of that. And it's really the
same thing no matter the platform that
you're using.
And so, the way that I have this MCP
server configured is just with this um
mcp.json file. And if you're curious how
I set this up,
this is the crazy thing, guys, is that
you can have Cloud Code help you with
anything. It has access to its own
documentation. So, if you say, you know,
help me copy over Cole's commands, and
you just give it the path, it can bring
all that into your own project. Or you
say, help me set up the Atlassian MCP
server, it'll search the web, it'll pull
the exact configuration, it knows to
create a file called mcp.json,
it'll set up everything for you. The the
time in in our world where we had to be
technical to do these kinds of things is
no longer here, right? Like a product
manager, a QA engineer can use Claude
code to do any part of their job just
like a developer can because you don't
have to know how to run commands or set
up MCP servers anymore. I mean, yes,
it's still helpful just in case the
coding agent trips up. So, it's faster
for a developer.
But uh also coding agents are really
good at debugging things. If the MCP
server doesn't connect right away, you
can ask it like, "Hey, I'm getting this
error. Help me figure it out." Maybe
like search the web for some more
Atlassian documentation, for example.
And so, really for like all these
things, I didn't configure that all
myself. Like I have my repository of
commands and skills. I pointed Claude
code there and I said, "All right,
Claude, for this AI transformation
workshop that I'm doing with Lior, I
want you to set up a brand new
repository and bring in my resources and
customize it to work with Jira instead
of GitHub, for example." And it just did
all of that for me.
So, a little bit meta there, but I hope
that demonstration is um is cool just to
see like how easy it is to get anything
configured in your AI coding
environment. And so, for all these
resources that I share with you, you
don't even have to bring them in
yourself.
So, we can see that it created all of
the stories here, and then it asked me a
question like, "Do you want to push to
Jira now?" So, I said, yes, and now it's
going to take advantage of that
Atlassian MCP server to populate
everything.
And so, I don't think we'll have it yet.
Let me refresh the page, but we'll in
just a second here, we'll start to see
things get populated. I think it's in
the middle of reasoning through that.
Okay. Yep, so we can see that the token
count go up as it is formulating those
tool calls, basically. So, the agent is
performing these operations under the
hood. And we're almost done with the
first step, by the way.
And once we get into the pivot loop,
things go pretty quickly because we're
doing so much of the work up front with
our ideation. So, we're getting to this
stage right now where we are getting our
tickets in Jira, and then we'll pick a
ticket, and then this is where we just
rip through the implementation with the
pivot loop.
So, all right, let's go back to Claude
and see where we are at.
All right, so calling at Atlassian seven
times. You can also in Claude do control
O so that you can see the full tool call
if you want some more visibility into
what it's doing. So, it's using the
create issue MCP tool.
It's got my ID, the project, all the
things that we specified as parameters
like the epic,
and the green circle here means that the
tool call actually finished. So, I'll do
control O to decompress again, and then
go back over, and now when I refresh,
we'll see some or maybe even all of the
issues created.
Or tickets, I should say. Take a look at
that. So, we don't have all of them yet.
It's in the middle of running those tool
calls, but we have things populated
already. And the cool thing here is if
we click into any one of these,
like
let's say I'll just click into the first
one for example, AT-14. If I click into
this, we have a lot of context given
here in the ticket as well. So, another
really cool thing is like for a product
manager, usually your description isn't
even going to be this good because you
don't have full context for the more
technical details. So, you can also use
Claude to provide more context to the
developers up front if you want to work
with it to, you know, create this kind
of issue description. And of course, for
the ticket descriptions, it's entirely
up to you and your commands for what
exactly you'd put here. Like in my
create stories command, I specifically
said I want the story and acceptance
criteria.
And then we could even add more context
here. Like we could have some more
research on how the coding agent would
recommend doing this. We could put that
as a comment here. Sometimes my Claude
code will actually do that by itself.
It's cool to see.
Um so, yeah, it's actually it is so it's
adding technical notes as comments to
each of the issues. So, not only are we
creating issues, but we're providing
more context as the coding agent has
done some research for each of the
implementations. Like looking into the
code base, providing those initial
suggestions for how we'd build each one
of these things.
And so, I'll let that run in the
background here cuz that's not like
super important for me to have finished
before I go to the next thing for you
guys.
And the next thing is really like let's
just pick one of these and let's work on
it. Right? Like at this point at an
organization level,
the product manager would take this list
list and send it over to the development
team. You know, you might have some
scrum meeting or whatever to talk about
these things and and again refine things
if you uh need to like fix up any of
these issues. And then you go on to the
development. Or if you are a solo
developer, then these might be GitHub
issues that you're now going to handle
one at a time.
And so, we just need to pick one of
these to work on.
And uh let's see.
I'm trying to think like uh maybe the
audience vote page would be a good one.
As an audience, I want mobile first page
that shows only active questions, lets
me submit my answer, auto advances when
the presenter moves on. That's a decent
one. What else could I work on here? I
mean, there's a lot of good features.
I'm trying to like think of like the
best one that would be good for a live
demonstration.
Uh presenter projection page. Actually,
this this is a good one here cuz that's
actually what I was planning for my
prep. So, I want a full screen page that
shows active questions, animated bar
chart, real-time updates as things are
coming in. That's definitely something
that we're we're missing right now cuz
this looks pretty bland for the results
page.
So, we'll tackle this issue first.
And the really cool thing is the input
into our development process just is
this issue.
And that's actually something I've been
doing a lot more recently with AI coding
assistance is
my input to writing the code is always
some artifact. Like for me personally,
uh I do a lot kind of as more of like a
solo developer or I'm working on open
source projects. So, usually the GitHub
issues is actually my entry point. So,
I'll put my artifacts here. I just
wanted to show Jira because that's how
so many teams work. But, uh your Jira
tickets, like that is the input.
And so, going into the pivot loop here,
we're going to go through a similar
first step where we're just going to
explore our solution. And the input into
this is just one of the tickets that we
pick. So, the developer takes that work.
You can use the Jira MCP to assign
yourself. And then, we start exploring
the solution.
And so, for planning with AI coding, you
always have two layers. You have the
project level planning, and that's
everything that we did here.
Right? Like this is like the PM level
planning.
And then, you have the task planning.
And that is the individual ticket level.
And the important thing that I I've
already explained a little bit here, but
I just want to be like really clear on
this, is the layer one planning is
higher level. Here are the features that
we want to build or the bugs we want to
fix. At this point, we are not digging
into the code. Now that we're taking a
single ticket for layer two, this is
where we get more in the weeds of
things. This is where we're going to
analyze the code base, the
documentation, figure out what parts of
the code base we actually have to touch.
We're starting to dive that deep.
And it's really helpful for the coding
agent to do this two-step process
because then now that we're getting
really into the weeds of things, we
already have a lot of context for what
we want to build overall. At this point,
the ticket has translated the
stakeholder or business requirements,
whatever you want to call it, and we may
be even have some higher-level
recommendations for what part of the
code we want to touch. And now, we're
just really getting into that. So, just
like creating our PRD, when we are
creating the actual implementation, we
start very unstructured. We're just
going to have a conversation with our
coding agent figuring out how should we
go about solving this problem, fixing
this bug, you know, implementing this
new feature, whatever that is. And then
we go from unstructured to structured.
So, this is very similar, like creating
a plan for implementation is very
similar to creating a PRD. And we're
going to have a command for planning out
the feature and just like we have a
command for creating our PRD.
And so, I'll show you guys what this
looks like right now. So, I'm going to
go back into my code base here.
And I'm going to begin a brand new
conversation. So, let me escape out of
this. I have a brand new conversation
with Claude. Because you can imagine
that like you as a developer, you are
picking up a single ticket and you don't
have any context around creating the PRD
or stories or anything. So, we're going
to pretend like this conversation
doesn't exist because it's going to be a
someone else doing this or maybe you
doing it at a different time. So, brand
new conversation. The first thing that I
always do when I am preparing for an
implementation is I run what is called a
prime command. So, another example of if
you're going to prompt a coding agent to
do something over and over again, just
turn it into a prompt, turn it into a
command. Cuz that way we don't have to
type it out again.
And so, this prime command, quite
simply, its job is to walk a coding
agent through understanding the code
base. We want to know what we already
have to help us think about what comes
next, right? So, we're going to load
external context, which this is where we
can specify Confluence pages or Jira
tickets that we wanted to understand. In
our case, we are actually going to
specify a Jira issue, right? We're going
to understand the code base from the
lens of this Jira ticket, this new thing
that we want to build. But also, aside
from that, we're just going to generally
understand the code base. So, we're
going to study the features, we're going
to study app routes, we're going to
check recent Git commits. I love using
Git as long-term memory for my coding
agents. So, a lot of times, what you've
done recently in a code base is going to
help guide what you do next, cuz you're
going to look at like the code patterns
you followed for recent commits and
things like that. This is a a very, very
powerful part
of any new conversation with a coding
agent. And obviously, the steps that you
want your coding agent to go through to
analyze the code base is very custom to
your code base. So, all of the commands
that I have here are starting points for
you, but you're always going to get the
most out of them if you customize the
commands to your process, your
architecture, your code bases.
And so, I'll start by running a
prime here. And one of the arguments
that we have is a comma-separated list
of Jira issues. And so, for example, uh
going back to our browser here in Jira,
um I just want to use
um this issue right here.
So, the ID for it is AT23
for our uh presenter projection page.
So, I'll do  prime and then just
AT23. So, it's going to understand the
entire code base, but also from the lens
of this issue. So, first it'll use the
Atlassian or Jira MCP to pull that
context. I can do control O and we can
see right here
that uh first it's listing accessible
resources, and then it's going to call
the tool to get that specific issue.
Performing a bunch of reads here, also
looking at the Git logs in parallel.
There's just a ton of context loading
that it's doing at the exact same time
here. Now, you want to be careful to not
load too much context into your coding
agent, cuz it's not like you want, you
know, 50% of your coding agent's context
window to be just loaded with a bunch of
research it's doing.
But we definitely want to load in the
core files and the core history of what
we've done recently. And so if you ever
want to, you know, tweak that lever of
how much context you're bringing into a
session up front, it's just you change
the prime command, right? Like you
change this over time. Like maybe you
only load in the first part of a Jira
issue or you only read from this part of
the code base. It's totally up to you
for how you formulate your commands to
optimize things for your process. So
here we go. Project context loaded. We
are going to be handling the presenter
projection page, so pulled full context
there. Gives me a quick summary of my
code base.
And um yeah, I think we're we're good to
go. Um though it actually it actually
says something interesting here. So this
is really cool. This is a good uh live
teaching moment. It is able to
recognize, based on querying my state in
Jira, that there are some blockers that
we need to take care of before we could
really go on to AT-23. So it understands
the dependency mapping. That is actually
one of the things that I have built into
create stories here where it can help
you understand dependencies. So maybe we
would actually have to handle AT-22 with
a QR code first. And um I think this is
this is something that we'll take on. So
maybe we'll do like, "Okay, look at
AT-22.
What do we need to implement for that?"
Right? We're starting very unstructured
in our planning here. We're actually
shifting gears right away, which is
totally okay, but we're just going to
have it get a little bit of
understanding of this feature that we
want to build. And we'll start to ideate
there.
So we're going to explore how we want to
build this, understand the code base,
and then get into that uh structure plan
that we'll go and send into
implementation.
And so at this point uh we have full
context from the issue,
but now we just do a little bit of
exploration. And what this looks like
totally is up to your own process. In
fact, this is one of the things that I
don't actually have as a command because
it's very free form at this point. So, I
can, you know, for example, go into my
speech text tool and say,
"All right, let's build AT-22. I want
you to spin up a few sub-agents to
research the code base and help me
ideate around uh how I would build this
new feature into our poll application."
So, just like a really quick prompt
here. And also showing you sub-agents
because sub-agents is something that I
use all of the time for research. If you
aren't familiar, sub-agents is basically
a way for you to spin up a uh
sub-process, another agent that runs
under the hood to go and look at a bunch
of things or perform a bunch of work and
then report back a summary to our main
Claude code agent here. And it's really
powerful for research because when we
are exploring a code base or doing web
research, we are loading in tens of
thousands of tokens of information.
Like, you can see that this one already
loaded in 32,000 tokens. We are going to
completely overwhelm our main agent if
we had it do all of the research by
itself.
And with research, you really only need
a quick summary at the end, right? Like,
here are generally the files that we
have to edit. Or if you're doing web
research, like, here are the core
articles that you should read that would
help with um best practices for this
tech stack. So, we've already used over
100,000 tokens here, but we only have a
few thousand tokens that are returned
back to our main agent. And so, yes,
with Claude code, with we now have the 1
million token limit with Opus, and there
are a lot of other models through Codex
and get out copilot and everything where
you have 1 million tokens. But, here's
the thing. Just because you can fit a
million tokens into a large language
model does not mean that you should,
because they get overwhelmed just like
people do. So, we want to deploy
strategies for managing context well.
Sub-agents is one of the best strategies
for that.
So, we just have to wait for these three
exploration agents to finish, and then
our main agent will get back a summary,
so it can reason. We can see that these
are all done now. So, it'll reason about
what the sub-agents did, and then it'll
provide me a final output here with its
recommendation for how we can handle
this Jira ticket.
And so, at this point, going back to our
diagram here, we're still at this
initial exploration, right? Like, we're
going to explore ideas, architecture,
concepts, tech stack. I'm not going to
go through each one of these things
right now for the sake of speed.
But, this is our chance to ask
questions. Or, like we did when we
created the PRD, have it ask us
questions as well. Because it's
important to remove assumptions going
into writing the actual code. It might
even be more Well, probably not more
important than assumptions in the PRD,
cuz the PRD is so high-stakes, but it it
is very important as well. So, we go
through this process where once we feel
confident that we're on the same page
with the coding agent, then we'll run a
command that'll create a structured
markdown document for our plan. We want
again, we we want the output of our
planning process to be a single
artifact, and that artifact is going to
contain all of the information that the
coding agent needs to do the actual
implementation.
And so, I'll show what that looks like
in a little bit, but first I want to
actually invoke the command to create
the plan, and then I'll explain more how
it works, just so that we can have
things move along well for us here.
So, here's a synthesis with real
decisions to make. Here's what we know,
okay, and three decisions worth making
before coding. So, it's asking me some
questions here. I'm going to blitz past
these for the sake of demonstration.
But, it is worth taking the time with
this usually. So, I'll do plan.
This is my command where I can now
describe the feature that I want to
build. So, I'm just going to say here go
with your
recommendations and create the plan for
AT-22.
So, I'm just going to give it permission
here to just pick whatever it wants.
Usually though, it would be worth taking
your time and answering these things and
having it ask you more questions as
well. So, while this planning command
runs, not to be confused with the plan
mode in Claude code, this is a separate
command that I have created right here.
It's very similar to the create PRD
plan.
Where we have phases laid out like
here's the research you should do
initially, explore the code base, make
sure you have full understanding for how
we're going to implement it, then create
the plan file. So, just like we created
a PRD.md,
we're now creating a plan.md.
And it has our structure. So, we want a
summary, a user story. It's going to be
similar to the PRD, but now we're
getting into the weeds of how we're
actually going to implement it. And so,
for example, one thing that we
definitely didn't have in our PRD
command
is the patterns to follow. Like here's
here's how we're coding things. Here are
the files that need to be changed.
Here's the task order, everything we're
going to execute down to the individual
level of the files that we're going to
create and update or maybe the commands
that we're going to run for testing. So,
also laying out out front. How do we
want our coding agent to validate its
own work?
Because when we get into the
implementation, we're going to send this
plan into the coding agent. We are going
to delegate all of the coding to the
coding agent. And the only reason that
I'm comfortable doing that is because I
still find myself in the driver's seat
because I'm a part of the planning
process. I'm iterating on the plan. I'm
doing the exploration and having it ask
the right questions. And so, we'll have
it write the code, and then we'll also
have it do some of the validation,
right? Like, we can have the coding
agent, right after it does the
implementation, we can have it write the
unit tests, write the integration tests,
do the linting and the type checking,
and take care of all of these things.
Not that it's going to be perfect, but
the point is we want it to take care of
as much validation as possible, so that
by the time control passes back to us
for our human validation, there's less
that needs to be corrected. Right? We
want to reduce us being the bottleneck
for actually shipping the code that
we're creating with the help of our
coding agents.
And so, I'll jump back over to the code
base here, and we can see that our plan
file is created. I'll take a look at
this really quick. Uh just another one
of those things that I don't want to
spend the time iterating on too much
right now, but we have the summary of
our work.
Uh we have the decisions that we've
locked in. These are the things that we
would have been working with the coding
agent to establish. And then, um we even
have like the individual files that need
to be created
and updated, and then we have the task
list.
So, usually the task list, you don't
create Azure tickets, right? Cuz this is
like so granular that this is for a
single coding agent implementation. So,
you let the coding agent handle an
internal task list as it is writing the
code. And then, we have the
self-validation.
So, it's going to be running the type
checking and linting and unit testing.
We can also have it do end-to-end
testing if we wanted to use browser
automation tools with um
you know, the agent browser CLI, for
example. So, that's actually one of the
skills that I have for you guys here. It
can spin up the browser and navigate
through it and like create polls and and
vote on the polls just like a user
would.
And so, for the sake of speed, I won't
do that, but you can have coding agents
do very, very end-to-end testing. You
want it to validate as much as possible.
So, the important thing here is once you
have iterated on the plan and you're
confident in everything,
you actually don't do the implementation
right here.
We want to start a brand new session
with Claude code. So, I'm going to open
up a a fresh blank slate with Claude.
The reason that I want to do this
is because when you are working with AI
coding assistants, you want to make sure
that they are as focused as possible.
And it's important to be focused in
order to be focused to do your planning
and implementing in separate sessions.
Because also, the coding agent has
probably built up a lot of bias
throughout this conversation as you've
been working with it. We want it to have
a fresh set of eyes on the problem going
into implementation.
And so, of course, I have an execute
command. And so, all I have to do is
implement and then I give it the
path to the plan that I created in the
prior session. And the whole point of
this markdown artifact is that it has
all of the context that the coding agent
needs to implement cuz it has the
summary, it has the recommended files to
change, and the task list, and the
validation strategy. There's no reason
for us to stay within this other context
window in the first place. So, I can
send off this command. It's going to
read the plan, and then it's going to
walk through the process I have in the
implement command to do the
implementation and the validation. And
this um command that I have for
implementation is actually very very
concise.
It's uh only like uh a couple of hundred
lines long here because really it's the
the plan that guides the entire
development.
The main thing that I'm walking it
through here is just the process of, you
know, loading the plan, preparing the
implementation, like maybe making a new
Git branch for example, like any kind of
of uh process that you have in your
usual software develop life cycle for
how you want an engineer to work, we're
just encoding that into the command
here.
We want to make sure that we're uh
verifying any kinds of assumptions. So,
we're also sort of doing like a second
pass on the plan before we go into to
implementation.
So, yeah, then describing how we want to
do validation, for example, when we want
to pass control back to the user,
outlining all of that for the agent.
And so, going back to our diagram here,
we're in this step right now. Right? We
we've cut a fresh session, sent the plan
into implementation,
and then we'll wait for it to write the
code, do all of its own validation, and
then we'll also step in and we'll do a
code review. Right? And it's not like
you have to do this.
Uh some people are are a big fan of just
shipping the code right to production
and having the coding agent do its own
work. I'm I'm not a fan of that myself.
I still the engineer in me still wants
to review all the code. So, for any like
serious production coding that I'm
doing, I still am reviewing all of the
code myself and then also doing manual
testing. And so, we can see that after
we do the implementation, like I'll
refresh the page here and we'll we'll
check out this new feature. Like we'll
see the QR code that's generated and
we'll make sure that's all working
before we would actually be confident
to, you know, merge that pull request
into our main branch, for example, or
whatever that looks like for your
software development life cycle going
into production.
So, that review is important.
And um you know, while we wait for the
coding agent to run through everything
here, you can see that it created its
internal task list based on the plan.
It's writing the code, doing all the
testing. It's actually going to get
through this feature pretty quick cuz I
purposely built a simple one. Uh but as
it is doing this, I want to quickly talk
about the last part of the system here.
Um and then of course, after this, we'll
we'll quickly get into time for Q&A with
uh
with Lior, too.
So, the last thing I want to talk about
is system evolution.
So, when whenever we do a pivot
it is very very far from guaranteed
that the implementation will be perfect.
Coding agents are not perfect. They are
non-deterministic by nature. Even if we
work super super hard to align with it
in the planning phases, there are still
going to be mistakes.
But the powerful part of this system is
we don't have to just treat the bug as a
one-off fix that we address and then
move on to the next pivot loop or move
on to that next ticket. We can spend
some time to fix to also fix the system
that allowed the bug.
And what I mean by that is we can have a
sort of, you know, retroactive session
with the coding agent where we say,
"Okay, Claude, you allowed this problem
to creep into my code base. I want you
to dive into your AI layer.
Like take a look at the at your rules.
Take a look at your commands and skills,
the process, the workflow that I brought
you through, and I want you to identify
things that we could improve there so
that this kind of issue doesn't happen
again.
Like for example, maybe it broke
something in the polling here where
um
I don't know. Let's say that like all of
a sudden the website looks really ugly
when it when it built this new feature
cuz it didn't like create the same like
it didn't create the component in the
same style as the rest of our code base.
Well, maybe that means that there's
something in our global rules that we
have to update for like our style
conventions.
Or maybe we need to build something into
our our validate workflow where whenever
we validate a code base, we make sure
that like any new front-end component
that we build is in compliance with the
styles of our other components that are
already in the code base. Just kind of a
random example I'm giving you there, but
the point is generally when your coding
agent does something wrong, there's
going to be something in the context you
give it that you can improve to not
necessarily for sure fix the problem,
but you're using it as an opportunity to
continue to evolve your AI layer, making
your rules more specific over time,
making your workflows more reliable. And
the best part of this is when you use
every single Jira ticket as a
potentially an opportunity to improve
your system, you get to improve the
whole process for everybody. Because you
can check in your rules and commands and
skills into source control just like
your code base, the entire team can
reuse these things and you can even
create pull requests to update commands
just like you create pull requests to
update your code base. So, you can do
code reviews making sure that everyone's
in line with the changes you're making.
I know that sounds like a decent amount
of work, but it's so high leverage.
Because every single time you improve a
command or a skill, it might save
engineers dozens and dozens of hours
going forward because you've now made
the validation process more reliable or
you've made the style conventions
respected more often, whatever that
might end up looking like.
And so, really like the four things that
I generally improve over time in a code
base is my commands, my on-demand
context. This could also even mean like
things in Confluence. You just, you
know, optimize your documents in
Confluence for AI understanding.
Your global rules and then also of
course like your plan and PRD templates.
You might want to define and fix gaps in
those over time.
And so, for every single code base, I'm
constantly doing this.
Right? Like if I have a pivot loop where
there is some kind of major issue, I
step outside of the pivot loop to do
this system evolution.
I will update things that I created up
front and then I'll go into the next
pivot loop.
And uh if if actually there are no
issues at all and the coding agent
completely rocked that Jira ticket, then
literally you just go loop right back,
right? You go through the planning
process, you load that next Jira ticket,
and you go through the process. So, it
becomes very, very cyclical. There's
basically two loops here. You have the
inner loop when everything's working
well and you're just chugging through
the work with the help of your coding
agent. And then you have the outer loop
when you're taking some time to reflect
and make your your better.
So, it's not like you always have to do
the outer loop, but I encourage you to
do it pretty often. Because not only are
you improving your your commands in
other parts of your system here, but you
are also customizing your process to
your specific code base over time. It's
like what I said, all of the commands
and skills that I have for you guys
here, they're a starting point, but
they're more general, right? Like if you
want to really optimize something for
your process, you're going to start with
these, find opportunities to make them
more specific to your validation
strategy or your planning strategy,
whatever that might be.
So, I hope that makes sense. I mean,
that really is the whole process at a
high level here. And uh so, I'm going to
head back to Claude here and see where
we are at. Okay, so the implementation
is complete. We did it in a branch cuz
our implementation command told it to.
We ran all of our validation here. Here
are the files that are changed. It's
giving us a summary of everything that
was done. It says that the
implementation matched the plan. So, I
also have a part of the process here.
This is actually something I did
recently for my system evolution where
after it does the implementation, it
looks at the code and compares it to the
plan to make sure that we didn't
deviate. And then it also used the uh
MCP server from Atlassian to update the
ticket. So, there's a lot of the admin
work that we did as well, you know,
creating the branch, creating the pull
request, updating the Jira ticket. We
don't have to have the developer spend
their time doing that stuff
retroactively. So, now if I go back and
I refresh my page here in Jira,
we can see that uh everything is to do
except for this one piece of work that
we picked up here. And I believe I think
I think it also said there was even a
comment. Yep, here we go. So, it also
posted a comment with full details. And
maybe this is more, you know, context
than we'd really want as a comment on a
Jira ticket, but if you have a problem
with this, then that would, you know,
also be an opportunity for system
evolution where you just specify in the
implement command, once you're done with
the implementation, here Here a more
concise version of context that I'd want
you to comment on the Jira ticket. So
now we can have this going into a code
review, send it off to, you know, your
VP to go and review, or you know,
whatever that is.
So pretty cool. And then we can also
test this in the application here.
So I'm going to refresh here. I'll
create a new poll. Um let's say what's
for lunch. And we'll just say
um spicy mango
chicken
or spicy mango beef. All right, cool. So
I'll create this poll.
And uh I don't actually see the QR code.
I might need to restart the application.
I think that might be why. So let me go
back here and say uh all right, I want
you to restart the application and then
use the agent browser skill so you can
visit it and make sure we have the QR
code. And then let let me know like how
I can see the QR code myself.
All right, so I yeah, I think I just
have a stale version of the application.
Um yeah, so
I also I mean if I want to like look at
more context, I can literally just go to
the ticket here.
So we have a server helper. I mean, this
is like a bit more technical. Like
honestly, I I would probably rather have
a higher level overview of what was
actually built. Uh again, something you
could just change in the command.
Um but yeah, so let me go ahead and jump
back over, see what Claude said.
Um
code utility. There's no consumer of it
yet. Oh, I got it. Okay, so it built out
the code, but we need to actually make
it so that the front end consumes it. Um
I want you to quickly uh implement the
consumer. Just really fast. No
validation, no Jira ticket. Just go and
add this right now so that I can see it
live.
Okay, so that that's my bad. I didn't
catch the fact that this was just
getting the pipe the piping in place.
And then it is that follow-up issue that
we're originally looking at that does
the presentation. So that's on me. So
every everything is working as intended,
but we just have to
Okay, so So, created a QR demo page.
So we can we can quickly look at that.
So, we'll see that in a second once it
um
once it uh does its own validation. So,
I I'm also showing a live demonstration
of the agent browser
where we can see it open up the website.
And uh it'll even like take a screenshot
to and vi- validate things visually,
too. And then of course, in parallel, we
can do the exact same thing. So, I'll go
back to the application and then I'll
just do QR demo.
Pretty cool. So, yeah, I know that uh
this is just a placeholder here, but I
told it to build something quick to
validate to the piping that we put in
place. And so then when we go on to the
next issue, the one that was depending
on this, then that's when we build in
the full presentation view and actually
use the the QR code for real. And again,
the point of this isn't to show the full
application, but just the process that
uh builds these kinds of things.
So,
all right. Uh that that is that is
really the process as a whole. We've
covered it We've covered it all from
planning all the way to system evolution
and creating those pull requests,
getting that code into production.
And uh I do want to reiterate that like
this process takes a good amount of
time.
It's It's not like you're going to blitz
through something as fast as me. It It
can be if you want, but uh the important
thing is even if you do take a lot of
time iterating on the plans and
validating the code, it's still going to
save you so many hours of work creating
those documents, updating things in
Jira, writing the code. You The The days
are gone now of going to Stack Overflow
in order to uh get your questions
answered. You don't have to
copy and paste and be a Stack Overflow
warrior anymore.
So, yeah, there you go. That is the full
process for AI coding. It's foundational
and simple enough where you can take
this and mold it to whatever your
software development process is,
standardizing things across your team
with the AI layer as well.